I knew either you today we're going to
learn why a programming language like
Python is a slower then a programming
language like C by the way I said slower
I didn't say slow slower all programming
languages are very fast okay they do
things fast in our computer faster than
our brains can do it so they're all fast
some of them are slow work doesn't mean
they're slow computers do not understand
humans computers speak zeros and ones
now humans we speak code in nutrition
programming language so we say for
example if else function variable we do
all the stuff right as you can see we
speak different languages code is here
zeros and ones are here two different
languages now there has to be a way of
translating if-else function whatever
two zeros and ones that produce in the
middle is called compilation or
interpretation let me give you an
example of interpretation and an example
of compilation so right now I'm in
Turkey here they speak Turkish
I speak English so I don't understand if
I'm walking down the street and some
Turkish person comes to me and they
start speaking I wouldn't know what
interpretation would do is that I will
have literally my friend here an
interpreter that will be speaking to my
ear and translating everything to
English I am getting some Turkey's
message here and my friend is
immediately translating everything into
English to my ear that is interpretation
it happens in real time now what is
compilation compilation doesn't happen
in real time compilation first my friend
will go my friend will listen to them
and then once my friend
understand the sentences once my friend
understands what they mean
my friend will translate the entire
message to me that is compilation versus
interpretation one of them
interpretation is done in real time and
the other one is done
not every attempt that that's what makes
a programming language is slower and
faster for example Python is interpreted
and C is compiled so on Titan there is
always a person here speaking to the
computer the zeros and the ones that he
needs to get for every line and that
could be slow that could be a slow
process because it is always a middle
man in the middle between your Python
code and the zeros and ones now when you
work with something like C C is compiled
that means that after you finish your
program you're going to press compile
the compiler will translate all your
code into zeros and ones and then you
will be able to open your program and of
course it will be faster because there
is no middleman there your code will be
comes using once immediately when you
open the program you will be seducing
ones there is no middleman there now
another example of this of white
difference between interpretation versus
compilation if my friend isn't is my
interpreter right here and the Turkish
person maybe he speaks a word that my
friend doesn't know my friend will say
OOP sorry I don't know and then we're
gonna be lost right that would be
interpretation now
if it was compilation and that Turkish
person it speaks to my friend some word
he doesn't know my friend will stop and
say like hey I don't know that word
change the world because I'd need to
translate that and I don't understand
that word that would be the same thing
in compilation and interpretation when
we have errors for example on Python for
example or even JavaScript because it's
an interpreted language and it happens
in real time my code might have some
errors and I might don't know about
these errors until they happen and that
is not good at all I want to know about
my errors before they happen so I can
fix them but because it's interpreted it
would be real time now if it's compiled
for example when you have a mistake on C
or any compiled language when you try to
compile your program C will tell you
wait one second hold on that doesn't
work I don't understand that fix it so
you know that once you compile your
software using the C compiler for
example you know that that code doesn't
have a
because the compiler approved it
basically of course if you have an
interpreter there is a middleman if you
don't you have all the power of these
zeros and ones and you can access even
deeper parts of the computers without a
middleman that might be a little bit
slow so that's it I know I made big
generalizations on this video if you are
already a programmer and you're
experimented and you like the theory
then I know you can disagree with
something that I said but I allow myself
to generalize because that's easy to
explain concepts I know sometimes you
can make Python a compiled language
there are ways of doing that but
generally Python is interpreted and C is
compiled right thank you for watching I
hope that you understood a little bit
better about how we communicate with
computers and I hope that you like my
example of my turkeys and my translator
let me know what you think let me know
if you like this video share it with
your friends and don't worry about speed
really is not a big deal to choose the
fastest programming language in the
world not a big deal that's it thank you
very much thank you for watching see you
in the next one eat kimchi be happy Amy
bye